# Josh Adrian Trinidad

# Senior Fullstack Engineer

Cell: (678)308-5760 | Email: akatoirotech@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/josh-adrian-trinidad/

Github: <a href="https://github.com/AdminAkai">https://github.com/AdminAkai</a> Website: <a href="https://www.adminis.tech">https://github.com/AdminAkai</a> Website: <a href="https://www.adminis.tech">https://github.com/AdminAkai</a>

# Summary

**Senior Fullstack engineer** with **8+ years of experience**, specializing mostly in **React/Typescript**. Well-organized and collaborative team player with strong communication and analytical abilities, as well as a hard and efficient worker and self learner. Desiring to use previous software experience to obtain more opportunities for work to gain knowledge and growth as a scientist and creator.

### Skills

- React React 18<sup>^</sup>, WACG Compliant, semantic code, react-router-dom, moment, styled-components, ESLint, MaterialUI, React Toastify, Prettier, docx, lodash, immutable, formik, yup, react-hook-form, SVG Icon conversion, absolute imports
- Javascript / Typescript ECMAScript 2023^, semantic code Promises, Classes, Modules, Objects, JSON, DOM Manipulation, async/await, fetch, generator functions, promises, Types, Interfaces
- **NodeJS Node 18^, npm**, **Webpack**, package.json, package-lock.json, node\_modules, scripts, ECMAScript Modules
- Redux Redux, React Redux, Redux Toolkit, Redux Saga, Redux Thunk
- HTML & CSS
- AWS Lambda, AppSync, Amplify, S3, Cloudfront, AWS Certificate Manager
- SQL / NoSQL PostgreSQL, MongoDB, ORMs (Mongoose, Sequelize), ERDs
- Git Github, Git Bash, Git Commands, Branching, Cloning, Forking, Pushing, Pulling, Merging.
- Google Google Firebase, Google Domains
- UI/UX Figma, Wireframes, Prototyping
- **GraphQL Apollo GraphQ**L (Setting up Schemas, Creating Queries, Creating Mutations, Creating Subscriptions)
- Testing Jest, Playwright, React Testing Library, Test-Driven Development/TDD, Behavior-Driven Development/BDD, Red/Green/Refactor, Unit Testing, E2E Testing
- Frontend Development WACG Compliance, a11y, Postman, HTTP Methods, AJAX, RESTful Architecture, WebSockets, Micro Frontends, semantic code, Responsive Web Design, Single Page Applications (SPAs), Server Side Rendering (SSR), Memoization, Web Security

# Work Experience

### Senior Fullstack Engineer - LaborWorx, Atlanta GA, Remote

#### AUGUST 2022 - AUG 2023

- Used Typescript and React to build the entire frontend and its architecture, developing every
  module of reusable UI components in WACG Compliant and semantic code, promoting
  consistency across the project, essentially developing all of the frontend on my own on our team
  of three with the help of the backend developers and PM as the QA/testers for industry-changing
  work/hire platform LaborWorx.
- Designed new features of the project as well as streamlined/reworked old user flows and business logic in **React**
- Designed and developed responsive user interfaces using **React** and **Figma**, enhancing user engagement and interaction, sometimes with the collaboration of third party UX designers.
- Created new data types and columns in the backend in PostgreSQL
- Collaborated with internal backend developers to integrate frontend interfaces with Apollo
  Graphql and PostgreSQL, ensuring seamless data exchange.
- Collaborated with a third party mobile development team on data/user flows via Slack.
- Pair programmed and guided fellow team members on **React/Typescript** and **general frontend** development paradigms and best practices.
- Implemented state management solution, utilizing Redux (RTK) and Redux Saga to centralize and manage application state effectively.
- Setup and configured **Jest** for the project, migrated existing components into modularized files with their own test folders, wrote tests for unit/integrated testing.
- Optimized application performance, identifying and resolving bottlenecks through code optimization and performance tuning, making sure each LCP/FCP (largest contentful paint/first contentful paint) were less than 500ms with each interaction to next paint also being less than 100ms
- Actively participated in Agile development processes, including daily stand-ups, sprint planning, and retrospective meetings.
- CEO/Leadership team meetings to discuss future aspects of the project and future work.

### Senior Fullstack Engineer - ImagineX, Atlanta GA, Remote

#### AUGUST 2022 - APRIL 2023

- Built and designed new features of the project as well as streamlined/reworked old user flows and business logic in **React**, in **WACG Compliant** and **semantic** code
- Created new UI/UX designs for the project in Figma
- Guided and pair programmed other contracted Mid Level engineers on React/Typescript and general frontend development and best practices.
- Client-facing meetings to discuss future aspects of the project and future work
- Working on developing a industry-changing work/hire platform built in React with Amplify on AWS Services which I later re-architectured with Redux/Redux Saga for the frontend while collaborating with the team as they moved the project to PostgreSQL/Node and transitioned off of AWS Amplify
- Setup and configured Jest for the project, migrated existing components into modularized files with their own test folders, wrote tests for unit/integrated testing

### Contract Software Engineer - Winnona Partners, Atlanta GA, Remote

#### JULY 2021 - MARCH 2023

- Created In-House Trello Board using React, Redux, styled-components, and GraphQL on the AWS Amplify framework with NodeJS, written in semantic code, which is currently used by the company for outlining features and bugfixes for projects.
- Built features and bugfixed client mortgage CRM built using **AWS Amplify** framework. Redesigned entire pages using **MUI**, **React**, and **styled-components**.
- Wrote AWS Lambda function for handling events, tested on AWS Console and sending automated emails. Wrote auto generated event history using deep-diff npm. Refactored many constants and utility functions to match current client requests.
- Wrote code-splitting **React** containers that lazy load components.
- Wrote **custom hooks** and utility functions.
- Used **lodash** to write **GraphQL** mutations that clones, modifies, and updates cache locally alongside updating the backend.
- Paginated/Filtered **GraphQL** gueries if needed.
- Used Github and BitBucket for source control via git cli.
- Wrote **jest** tests for testing component rendering as well as utility functions using @testing-library/react and @testing-library/jest-dom utils.
- Wrote new schemas for Amplify GraphQL and generated queries/mutations. Updates to DynamoDB.
- Worked/Configured with ESLint.

### Contract Software Engineer - Big Pixel, Atlanta GA, Remote

#### MARCH 2020 - JULY 2020

- Worked with client GrammarFlip, a teaching application. Migrated application to newer version of
  create-react-app and Typescript, refactored old typescript to pass TSLint and ESLint,
  created interfaces and custom types. Created new diagnostic features for teachers and students
  using Redux and Typescript and NodeJS. Written to be WACG Compliant and in semantic
  code
- Worked on NDA project using Redux Saga and Typescript and NodeJS for making a scalable social media application that is WACG Compliant in semantic code, with other third party libraries (such as Cloudinary, styled-components, tailwindcss, semantic-ui, reselect, react for google/facebook logins).

### Contract Software Engineer - Noble Systems Corporation, Dunwoody, GA

#### JUNE 2015 - JANUARY 2018

- Used **CentOS** virtual machines for **Docker** containers for writing, reviewing, and running automated tests written in **Python(2.7)**. Such as a testing environment called Standalone, a simulated call center environment with virtual agents.
- Wrote **PostgreSQL** database SQL scripts for adding/updating data and creating tables/indexes as well as database migrations.
- Used **Team Foundation Server (TFS)** as source control to checkout code, commit code, and view history, like refactoring old code to work with current systems.
- More responsibilities include: making rpm builds through **Jenkins** before releasing to QA, updating tickets through internal bug tracker, and updating/creating internal wiki/documentation pages for the Research and Development department.

# All Skills/Experiences

- React react-router-dom, moment, styled-components, ESLint, MaterialUI, React Toastify, Prettier, docx, lodash, immutable, formik, yup, react-hook-form, SVG Icon conversion, absolute imports, custom hooks
- Javascript / Typescript Promises, Classes, Modules, Objects, JSON, DOM Manipulation, async / await, fetch, generator functions, Types, Interfaces
- **NodeJS** ver 18<sup>^</sup>, npm, package.json, package-lock.json, node\_modules, scripts, ECMAScript Modules
- Redux Redux, Redux Toolkit, Redux Saga, Redux Thunk
- AWS Lambda, AppSync, CodeCommit, CodePipeline, Amazon Pinpoint, Cloud Formation, Amplify, S3 bucket, AWS Console, Amazon Route 53, Cloudfront, AWS Certification Manager
- UI/UX Figma, Wireframes, Prototyping
- **GraphQL Apollo GraphQL** (Setting up Schemas, Creating Queries, Creating Mutations, Creating Subscriptions)
- Testing Jest, Playwright, Test-Driven Development/TDD, Behavior-Driven Development/BDD, Red/Green/Refactor, Unit Testing, E2E Testing
- Google Google Firebase, Google Domains
- Frontend Development WACG Compliance, a11y, Postman, HTTP Methods, AJAX, RESTful Architecture, WebSockets, Micro Frontends, semantic code, Responsive Web Design, Single Page Applications (SPAs), Server Side Rendering (SSR), Memoization, Web Security
- Backend Development Entity Relationship Diagrams (ERD), Database Schemas, Data Models, APIs, Databases, servers, Web Security
- Collaboration Tools Slack, Discord, Microsoft Teams, Microsoft Outlook, Google Meet, Google Workspaces
- Python Modules, Classes, Python3, Python2.7, Functions, Dictionaries, Django (configuration)
- Linux Unix, CentOS, Ubuntu, Linux Command Line, Vim, Grep, Shell Scripting, Systemd Files
- HTML5 & CSS3
- SQL / NoSQL PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Relational Databases, Nonrelational Databases, ORMs (Mongoose, Sequelize), ERDs
- Go (syntax, no professional experience)
- Git Github, Git Bash, Git Commands, Branching, Cloning, Forking, Pushing, Pulling, Merging.
- VSCode Terminal, Workspaces, Addons, config.json
- Docker Pulling, Running, Killing, Provisioning, Kubernetes (currently learning)
- Computer Assembly All Parts to Full Build
- Virtual Machines VirtualBox, MobaXterm
- Experience / Paradigms Object-Oriented Programming, Functional Programming,
   Data Types, Data Structures and Algorithms, Big O Notation, Agile
   Methodologies., Heroku, Netlify, Expo

## Education

# General Assembly (Code Bootcamp), Atlanta, GA

Software Engineering Immersive Cohort 24

SEPTEMBER 2019 - DECEMBER 2019

A 3 month long code bootcamp focused on fullstack engineering. Built rich, interactive, full-stack apps and dove into algorithms, data structures, design patterns, APIs, and more. Used **HTML5**, **CSS3**, **JavaScript**, **Python**, **Django**, **React**, **Express.js**, **PostgreSQL**, **MongoDB**, and more, as well as PaaS such as **Heroku** and **AWS** for deploying our applications.

## Georgia State University, Dunwoody, GA

BS in Computer Science (not graduated) AUGUST 2015 - JANUARY 2018

Cross Keys High School, Atlanta, GA

High School Graduate
AUGUST 2011 - MAY 2015